

I got my start with programming at my first job after finishing university, where I built simple web scrapers in Microsoft VBA to automate tasks, and many jobs I've had since then have touched on programming, which has been the thing I found most interesting about them.

I have been a self-trained freelance web developer for the past three years, but I wanted to get on to the next level. This is why I have started my journey to become a professional software developer by training at Makers Academy (London's leading programming bootcamp).

I want to create software that is not only useful for users, but also engaging and interesting to keep them coming back for more.

Skills

Team-Focused - During my final project at Makers, we took on React. While I already had some experience with React, a lot of the team hadn't. In order to accelerate our project and to progress as a group, I spent time making sure everyone had the necessary skills in React and Jest (the testing framework) to contribute as effectively as possible.

Project Organisation - During my time as a freelance web designer I often worked on several projects simultaneously. I manage my time effectively, focusing on tasks of high importance and urgency first. At Makers we often worked in groups on larger scale projects. Using XP/Agile methodologies and task tracking methodologies such as Kanban, I ensured our workflow was clear and efficiently managed.

Communication - Often I have needed to keep multiple stakeholders informed about progress, be they the project manager, a freelance client, or a teammate. Understanding each of their needs and clarifying the meaning of their questions allows me to give them the information they care about in a way they understand.

Technical Knowledge - I have worked with a variety of languages, technologies and softwares:

Languages Ruby, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Technologies Rails, Sinatra, Node.js, Express, jQuery, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,

TravisCI, Heroku, Surge

Testing RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Jest, Enzyme

Frameworks

Concepts XP/Agile methodology, TDD/BDD, Object Oriented Design, Remote

working, Pair programming, Continuous Integration & Deployment, Git

workflow, Code review, MVC Pattern, RESTful APIs

Tools VSCode, Git, Figma, Photopea (FOSS alternative to Photoshop),

Postman, Windows 10, Linux (Ubuntu), OSx

Hobbies and Interests

Improvised comedy - I perform live on stage with no script, based on audience suggestion. Skills from improv have great applications in the workplace too, such as active listening, generating ideas, building trust within teams, and working out of joy instead of fear.

Cycling - I enjoy cycling, especially e-bikes.

Running - I run to keep fit, and sometimes I enjoy it.

Projects

Mission-Ctrl - Group project. An arcade style game to learn VSCode shortcuts.

Bank Tech Test - A CLI program emulating a bank account, showcasing test driven development in 3 languages.

Neogram - A social media photo sharing web-app, inspired by instagram and neomorphism design.

Bowling Scorecard - An immersive bowling scorecard.

News Summary - A single page web app consuming the Guardian API, using vanilla HTML, CSS, and JS.

Experience

The Nursery Theatre Ltd (Nov 2017 to Present)

Digital Communication and Website Manager

Graphic and Web Designer (Aug 2017 to Present)

Freelance

Freedom Tech Ltd (Nov 2015 to

Jul 2017)

Marketing and Project Manager

Education

Makers Academy

(Feb 2020 to Jun 2020)

A 16 week intensive programming

bootcamp

FreeCodeCamp

(2018 - Present)

Responsive Web Design

Certification

University of Nottingham

(Sep 2011 to Jun 2015)

MSci Life Sciences, 2:1